import 'package:quiz_app_tutorial/models/question.dart';

const List<Question> gkQuestions = [
  Question(
    question: '1. What is the capital city of Japan?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Beijing',
      'b) Seoul',
      'c) Tokyo',
      'd) Bangkok',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '2. Who is known as the father of modern physics?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Isaac Newton',
      'b) Galileo Galilei',
      'c) Albert Einstein',
      'd) Stephen Hawking',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '3. What is the largest planet in our solar system?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Earth',
      'b) Jupiter',
      'c) Saturn',
      'd) Mars',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '4. In which year did the Berlin Wall fall?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) 1985',
      'b) 1987',
      'c) 1989',
      'd) 1991',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '5. Who wrote the play "Romeo and Juliet"?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) William Shakespeare',
      'b) Jane Austen',
      'c) Charles Dickens',
      'd) Mark Twain',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '6. What is the currency of Brazil?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Peso',
      'b) Real',
      'c) Baht',
      'd) Euro',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: "7. What is the world's longest river?",
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Mississippi River',
      'b) Amazon River',
      'c) Nile River',
      'd) Yangtze River',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '8. Who painted the Mona Lisa?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 2,
    options: [
      'a) Vincent van Gogh',
      'b) Pablo Picasso',
      'c) Leonardo da Vinci',
      'd) Michelangelo',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '9. In which year did the first moon landing occur?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 0,
    options: [
      'a) 1969',
      'b) 1972',
      'c) 1981',
      'd) 1994',
    ],
  ),
  Question(
    question: '10. What is the capital city of Canada?',
    correctAnswerIndex: 1,
    options: [
      'a) Toronto',
      'b) Ottawa',
      'c) Vancouver',
      'd) Montreal',
    ],
  ),
];
